Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
I know what it is you saw.
For it is also in my mind.
It is what will come to pass
if you should fail.
The Fellowship is breaking.
It is already begun.
He will try to take the Ring.
You know of whom I speak.
One by one, it will destroy them all.
If you ask it of me...
...I will give you the One Ring.
You offer it to me freely.
I do not deny that my heart
has greatly desired this.
In place of a Dark Lord,
you would have a queen...
...not dark but beautiful,
and terrible as the dawn!
Treacherous as the sea!
Stronger than the foundations
of the earth!
All shall love me...
...and despair.
I pass the test. I will diminish...
...and go into the West...
-...and remain Galadriel.
-I cannot do this alone.
You are a Ring-bearer, Frodo.
To bear a Ring of Power...
...is to be alone.
This is Nenya,
the Ring of Adamant.
And I am its keeper.
This task was appointed to you.
And if you do not find a way...
...no one will.
Then I know what I must do.
It's just...
...I'm afraid to do it.
Even the smallest person can change
the course of the future.
Do you know how the Orcs
first came into being?
They were Elves once.
Taken by the Dark Powers...
...tortured and mutilated.
A ruined and terrible form of life.
And now...
...perfected.
My fighting Uruk-hai...
...whom do you serve?
Saruman!
Hunt them down. Do not stop
until they are found.
You do not know pain.
You do not know fear.
You will taste Man-flesh!
One of the halflings carries
something of great value.
Bring them to me alive and unspoiled.
Kill the others.
Never before have we clad strangers
in the garb of our own people.
May these cloaks help shield you
from unfriendly eyes.
Lembas.
Elvish waybread.
One small bite is enough to fill
the stomach of a grown man.
How many did you eat?
Four.
Every league you travel south,
the danger will increase.
Mordor Orcs now hold the eastern shore
of the Anduin.
Nor will you find safety
on the western bank.
Strange creatures bearing the White Hand
have been seen on our borders.
Seldom do Orcs journey in the open
under the sun, yet these have done so.
By river you have the chance of outrunning
the enemy to the FallIs of Rauros.
My gift for you, Legolas,
is a bow of the Galadhrim.
Worthy of the skill
of our woodland kin.
These are the daggers of the Noldorin.
They have already seen service in war.
Do not fear, young Peregrin Took.
You will find your courage.
And for you, Samwise Gamgee...
...Elven rope made of hithlain.
Thank you, my lady.
Have you run out
of those nice, shiny daggers?
And what gift would a dwarf ask
of the Elves?
Nothing.
Except to look upon the lady
of the Galadhrim one last time...
...for she is more fair
than all the jewels beneath the earth.
Actually....
There was one thing.
No, no, I couldn't.
It's quite impossible.
Stupid to ask.
I have nothing greater to give...
...than the gift you already bear.
That choice is yet before her.
You have your own choice to make,
Aragorn.
To rise above the height of all
your fathers since the days of Elendil...
...or to fall into darkness
with all that is left of your kin.
Farewell, Frodo Baggins.
I give you the light of Eärendil...
...our most beloved star.
May it be a light for you
in dark places...
...when all other lights go out.
I have taken my worst wound
at this parting...
...having looked my last upon that
which is fairest.
Henceforth I will call nothing fair
unless it be her gift to me.
What was her gift?
I asked her for one hair
from her golden head.
She gave me three.
Gollum. He has tracked us since Moria.
I had hoped we would lose him
on the river.
But he's too clever a waterman.
And if he alerts the enemy
to our whereabouts...
...it will make the crossing
even more dangerous.
Have some food, Mr. Frodo.
-No, Sam.
-You haven't eaten anything all day.
You're not sleeping, neither.
Don't think I haven't noticed.
-Mr. Frodo--
-I'm all right.
But you're not.
I'm here to help you.
I promised Gandalf that I would.
You can't help me, Sam.
Not this time.
Get some sleep.
Minas Tirith is the safer road.
You know that.
From there we can regroup.
Strike out for Mordor from a place
of strength.
There is no strength in Gondor
that can avail us.
You were quick enough to trust
the Elves.
Have you so little faith
in your own people?
Yes, there is weakness.
There is frailty.
But there is courage also,
and honor to be found in Men.
But you will not see that.
You are afraid!
All your life, you have hidden
in the shadows.
Scared of who you are,
of what you are.
I will not lead the Ring within
a hundred leagues of your city.
Frodo.
The Argonath.
Long have I desired
to look upon the kings of old.
My kin.
We cross the lake at nightfall.
Hide the boats and continue on foot.
-We approach Mordor from the North.
-Oh, yes?
Just a simple matter of finding
our way through Emyn Muil...
...an impassable labyrinth
of razor-sharp rocks.
And after that, it gets even better.
Festering, stinking marshland
as far as the eye can see.
That is our road.
I suggest you take some rest
and recover your strength, Master Dwarf.
Recover my--
-We should leave now.
-No.
Orcs patrol the eastern shore.
We must wait for cover of darkness.
It is not the eastern shore
that worries me.
A shadow and a threat
has been growing in my mind.
Something draws near.
I can feel it.
Recover strength?
Pay no heed to that, young Hobbit.
Where's Frodo?
None of us should wander alone.
You, least of all.
So much depends on you.
Frodo?
I know why you seek solitude.
You suffer. I see it day by day.
You sure you do not suffer needlessly?
There are other ways, Frodo.
-Other paths that we might take.
-I know what you would say.
It would seem like wisdom
but for the warning in my heart.
Warning? Against what?
We're all afraid, Frodo.
But to let that fear drive us,
to destroy what hope we have...
-...don't you see that is madness?
-There is no other way.
I ask only for the strength
to defend my people!
-If you would but lend me the Ring.
-No.
-Why do you recoil? I am no thief.
-You are not yourself.
What chance do you think you have?
They will find you.
They will take the Ring.
And you will beg for death
before the end!
You fool!
It is not yours, save by unhappy chance!
It could have been mine.
It should be mine! Give it to me!
-Give it to me!
-No!
-No.
I see your mind.
You will take the Ring to Sauron!
You will betray us!
You'll go to your death,
and the death of us all!
Curse you!
Curse you and all the halflings!
Frodo?
Frodo.
What have I done?
Please, Frodo.
Frodo, I'm sorry!
Frodo?
-It has taken Boromir.
-Where is the Ring?
Stay away!
Frodo!
-I swore to protect you.
-Can you protect me from yourself?
Would you destroy it?
Aragorn.
Elessar.
I would have gone with you to the end.
Into the very fires of Mordor.
I know.
Look after the others. Especially Sam.
He will not understand.
Go, Frodo!
Run.
Run!
Mr. Frodo!
Find the halfling!
Elendil!
Aragorn, go!
Frodo!
Hide here. Quick!
Come on!
What's he doing?
He's leaving.
-No!
-Pippin!
Run, Frodo. Go on!
-Hey! Hey, you!
-Over here!
-This way!
-It's working!
-I know it's working! Run!
-The horn of Gondor.
-Boromir.
Run!
No.
-They took the little ones.
-Hold still.
Frodo. Where is Frodo?
I let Frodo go.
Then you did what I could not.
I tried to take the Ring from him.
-The Ring is beyond our reach now.
-Forgive me.
I did not see it.
-I have failed you all.
-No, Boromir.
You fought bravely.
You have kept your honor.
Leave it.
It is over.
The world of Men will fall.
And all will come to darkness...
...and my city to ruin.
I do not know what strength
is in my blood...
...but I swear to you,
I will not let the White City fall...
...nor our people fail.
Our people.
I would have followed you, my brother.
My captain.
My king.
Be at peace...
...son of Gondor.
They will look for his coming
from the White Tower.
But he will not return.
Frodo!
I wish the Ring had never come to me.
I wish none of this had happened.
So do all who live
to see such times...
...but that is not for them to decide.
All you have to decide...
...is what to do with the time
that is given to you.
Frodo, no!
Frodo!
-Mr. Frodo!
-No, Sam.
Go back, Sam!
-I'm going to Mordor alone.
-Of course you are.
And I'm coming with you!
You can't swim!
Sam!
I made a promise, Mr. Frodo.
A promise:
"Don't you leave him, Samwise Gamgee."
And I don't mean to.
I don't mean to.
Sam.
Come on.
Hurry! Frodo and Sam
have reached the eastern shore.
-You mean not to follow them.
-Frodo's fate is no longer in our hands.
Then it has all been in vain.
The Fellowship has failed.
Not if we hold true to each other.
We will not abandon Merry and Pippin
to torment and death.
Not while we have strength left.
Leave all that can be spared behind.
We travel light.
Let us hunt some Orc.
Yes!
Mordor.
I hope the others find a safer road.
Strider will look after them.
I don't suppose
we'll ever see them again.
We may yet, Mr. Frodo.
We may.
Sam...
...I'm glad you are with me.
Timing by Khuno
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/h7hc
Help other users to choose the best subtitles